<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>generative-art on Max Halford</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/tags/generative-art/</link><description>Recent content in generative-art on Max Halford</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</managingEditor><webMaster>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxhalford.github.io/tags/generative-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Morellet crosses with JavaScript</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/morellet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/morellet/</guid><description>The days I&amp;rsquo;m working on a deep learning project. I hate it but I promised myself to give it a real try. My scripts are taking a long time so I decided to do some procedural art while I waited. This time I&amp;rsquo;m going to reproduce the following crosses made by François Morellet. I saw them the last I went to the Musée Pompidou with some friends from university. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any smartphone anymore so one my friends was kind enough to take a few pictures for me, including this one.</description></item><item><title>Stella triangles with JavaScript</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/stella-triangles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/stella-triangles/</guid><description>Around the same time last year I visited the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art. Frank Stella&amp;rsquo;s compositions really caught my eye. When I saw them I started thinking about how I could write a computer program to imitate his work. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt to reproduce his so-called V Series.
Nice and simple right? Indeed in a lot of his work Frank Stella uses straight lines without much randomness.</description></item><item><title>Unknown pleasures with JavaScript</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/unknown-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/unknown-pleasures/</guid><description>No this blog post is not about how nice JavaScript can be, instead it&amp;rsquo;s just another one of my attempts at reproducing modern art with procedural generation and the HTML5 &amp;lt;canvas&amp;gt; element. This time I randomly generated images resembling the cover of the album by Joy Division called &amp;ldquo;Unknown Pleasures&amp;rdquo;.
According to Wikipedia, this somewhat iconic album cover is based on radio waves. I saw a poster of it in a bar not long ago and decided to reproduce the next time I had some time to kill.</description></item><item><title>Grid paintings à la Mondrian with JavaScript</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/mondrian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/mondrian/</guid><description>I was at a laundrette today and had just finished my book so I had some time to kill. Naturally I devised an algorithm for generating drawings that would resemble the grid-like paintings that Piet Mondrian made famous. With the benefit of hindsight I guess I could indulge in saner activities while waiting for my laundry to dry!
I went through different ideas but in the end I settled on a recursive approach.</description></item><item><title>Recursive polygons with JavaScript</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/recursive-polygons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/recursive-polygons/</guid><description>I like modern art, I enjoy looking at the stuff that was made at the beginning of the 20th century and thinking how it is still shaping today&amp;rsquo;s style. I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert, it&amp;rsquo;s just a hobby of mine. I especially like the Centre Pompidou in Paris, it&amp;rsquo;s got loads of fascinating stuff. While I was going through the galleries it struck me that some of the paintings were very geometrical.</description></item></channel></rss>