<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kaggle on Max Halford</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/tags/kaggle/</link><description>Recent content in Kaggle on Max Halford</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</managingEditor><webMaster>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxhalford.github.io/tags/kaggle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Organising a Kaggle InClass competition with a fairness metric</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/fairness-competition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/fairness-competition/</guid><description>Some context I co-organised a data science competition during the second half of 2020. This was in fact the 5th edition of the &amp;ldquo;Défi IA&amp;rdquo;, which is a recurring event that happens on a yearly basis. It is essentially a supervised machine learning competition for students from French speaking universities and engineering schools. This year was the first time that Kaggle was used to host the competition. Before that we used a custom platform that I wrote during my student years.</description></item><item><title>A short introduction and conclusion to the OpenBikes 2016 Challenge</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/openbikes-challenge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/openbikes-challenge/</guid><description>During my undergraduate internship in 2015 I started a side project called OpenBikes. The idea was to visualize and analyze bike sharing over multiple cities. Axel Bellec joined me and in 2016 we won a national open data competition. Since then we haven&amp;rsquo;t pursued anything major, instead we use OpenBikes to try out technologies and to apply concepts we learn at university and online.
Before the 2016 summer holidays one of my professors, Aurélien Garivier mentioned that he was considering using our data for a Kaggle-like competition between some statistics curriculums in France.</description></item></channel></rss>