<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>image-processing on Max Halford</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/tags/image-processing/</link><description>Recent content in image-processing on Max Halford</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</managingEditor><webMaster>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxhalford.github.io/tags/image-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comic book panel segmentation</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/comic-book-panel-segmentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/comic-book-panel-segmentation/</guid><description>Edit (2023-05-26) &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about the Kumiko project, which is exactly devoted to slicing comic book panels. There&amp;rsquo;s even a live tool. I discovered it thanks to being pinged on this issue.
Motivation I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been reading some comic books I used to devour as a kid. Especially those from the golden era of francophone comics: Thorgal, Lanfeust, XIII, Tintin, Largo Winch, Blacksad, Aldebaran, etc.
It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to get my hands on many of them.</description></item><item><title>Halftoning with Go - Part 2</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/halftoning-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/halftoning-2/</guid><description>The next stop on my travel through the world of halftoning will be the implementation of Weighted Voronoi Stippling as described in Adrian Secord&amp;rsquo;s 2002 paper. This method is more involved than the ones I detailed in my previous blog post, however the results are quite interesting. Again, I did the implementation in Go.
Notice the black dot in the middle of the white square? Overview I found a fair amount of resources about the method, most of them being implementations of Adrian Secord&amp;rsquo;s paper.</description></item><item><title>Halftoning with Go - Part 1</title><link>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/halftoning-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>maxhalford25@gmail.com (Max Halford)</author><guid>https://maxhalford.github.io/blog/halftoning-1/</guid><description>Recently I stumbled upon this webpage which shows how to use a TSP solver as a halftoning technique. I began to read about related concepts like dithering and stippling. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any background in photography but I can appreciate the visual appeal of these techniques. As I understand it these techniques were first invented to save ink for printing. However nowadays printing has become cheaper and the modern use of these technique is mostly aesthetic, at least for images.</description></item></channel></rss>